<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC 
   "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
   "docbook/docbookx.dtd">
<refentry id='manlifter.1'>
<refmeta>
<refentrytitle>manlifter</refentrytitle>
<manvolnum>1</manvolnum>
<refmiscinfo class='date'> Sun Nov 28 2004</refmiscinfo>
<refmiscinfo class='source'>manlifter</refmiscinfo>
<refmiscinfo class='productname'>manlifter</refmiscinfo>
<refmiscinfo class='manual'>Documentation Tools</refmiscinfo>
</refmeta>
<refnamediv id='name'>
<refname>manlifter</refname>
<refpurpose>mass-conversion script and test harness for doclifter</refpurpose>
</refnamediv>
<refsynopsisdiv id='synopsis'>

<cmdsynopsis>
  <command>manlifter</command>  
  <arg choice='opt'>-d <replaceable>option</replaceable></arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-e</arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-f <replaceable>listfile</replaceable></arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-h</arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-I <replaceable>mandir</replaceable></arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-m</arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-M</arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-o <replaceable>outdir</replaceable></arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-p <replaceable>patch-directory</replaceable></arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-P</arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-q</arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-v</arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-s <replaceable>section</replaceable></arg>
  <arg choice='opt'>-X <replaceable>exclude</replaceable></arg>
  <arg choice='plain' rep='repeat'><replaceable>name</replaceable></arg>
</cmdsynopsis>
<cmdsynopsis>
  <command>manlifter</command> <arg choice='opt'>-S</arg>  
</cmdsynopsis>
</refsynopsisdiv>

<refsect1><title>Description</title>

<para><command>manlifter</command> is a script that sequences
<citerefentry><refentrytitle>doclifter</refentrytitle><manvolnum>1</manvolnum></citerefentry>
to convert an entire manual-page tree to XML-Docbook, optionally also
generating HTML from the XML.  Another use is as a torture-test tool
for doclifter; it logs errors to standard output and collects
timings.</para>

<para>Called without any file arguments, manlifter tries to convert
all eligible man pages installed on the system, placing the resulting xml files
under <filename>xmlman</filename> in the current directory.  Each
successfully translated page foo.N is copied to manN/foo.xml beneath
the output directory, regardless of what source directory it came
from.
</para>

<para>A maniual page is considered ineligibile for batch conversion if
it contains text indicating it has been generated from DocBook masters
of from Doxygen.</para>

<para>For each source file examined, if the destination file exists
and is newer than the source, the conversion is skipped; thus,
incremental runs of <command>manlifter</command> do the least work
needed to keep the target XML tree up to date.  Likewise, in -h mode derived
HTML files are only made when necessary.</para>

<para>Stub pages that are just <markup>.so</markup> redirections are
translated to corresponding symlinks of XML files (and, with -h, HTML
files).</para>

<para><command>manlifter</command> may also be called with a single
file argument, which is interpreted as the stem name of a potential
manual page.  <command>manlifter</command> then searches all selected
manual sections for a matching page and attempts to convert it.  In
this case, a copy of the man page and the converted version are
dropped immediately beheath the output directory, with the names
foobar.man and foobar.man.xml, respectively.  This mode is normally
only of interest only to <command>doclifter</command> developers for
debugging that program.</para>

<para>In either of the above cases, <command>manlifter</command> will
uncompress the file if it has a <filename>.gz</filename>, 
<filename>.bz2</filename> or <filename>.Z</filename> suffix on the
name.</para>

<para>Options are as follows:</para>

<variablelist>
<varlistentry>
<term>-d</term>
<listitem><para>Pass the string argument to each doclifter call as options.
Each space-separated token in the string becomes a separate argument
in the call.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-e</term>
<listitem><para>Run in log-filter mode (mainly of interest to
<command>doclifter</command> developers).  In this mode,
<command>manlifter</command> reads a test log from standard input and
filters it in a a way dependent on the -f and -q options.  If neither
of these is given, messages from successful runs are stripped out and
only errors passed through to standard output.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-f</term>
<listitem><para>Normally, run doclifter on the files named by each line in the
argument file.  In error-filter mode the argument is instead
interpreted as a filtering regular expression.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-h</term>
<listitem><para>Also generate HTML translations into the output
directory. DocBook citerefentry markup is transformed to hyperlinks in
the directory, and a contents listing is generated to
<filename>index.html</filename>.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-I</term>
<listitem><para>Specify the root of the manual-page tree.  By default
this is <filename>/usr/share/man</filename>.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-m</term>
<listitem><para>Make a patch to correct the last page fetched. It is
copied, an editor is called on the copy (using the environment
variable <envar>$EDITOR</envar>), and then
<citerefentry><refentrytitle>diff</refentrytitle><manvolnum>1</manvolnum></citerefentry>
is called to drop the patch in the prepatch directory. Fails with an
error if such a patch is already present.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-M</term>
<listitem><para>Lift the specified files, then do the equivalent of
the -m option.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-o</term>
<listitem><para>Set the output directory into which
XML-DocBook translations will be dropped.  By default this is
<filename>xmlman</filename> under the current directory in batch mode, 
or the current directory otherwise.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-p</term>
<listitem><para>Interpret the argument as the name of a patch
directory (the default name is <filename>prepatch</filename> under the
current directory).  Each file named <filename>foo.N.patch</filename> is
interpreted as a patch to be applied to the manual page foo(N) before
doclifter translates it.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-P</term>
<listitem><para>Enable profiling using the Python hotshot module; this
is only useful for tuning <application>doclifter</application> so it
runs faster. Raw data is written to
<filename>manlifter.prof</filename>, and a digested report is appended
to the log on standard output.  Warning: the raw data files can become
huge, and the postprocessing for report generation can take as long
as the actual processing (or longer!).</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-q</term>
<listitem><para>Normally, pass the -q (quiet) option to each doclifter call.
In error-filter mode, return a list of files on which translation failed.
</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-v</term> <listitem><para>Pass the -v (verbose) option to each
doclifter call.  This option can be repeated to increase the verbosity
level.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-s</term>
<listitem><para>Specify a section to scan.  Use this with an argument;
it should not be necessary when doing a conversion of the entire
tree.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-S</term>
<listitem><para>Compile error statistics from a
<command>manlifter</command> logfile presented on standard input.
This option will be of interest mainly to <command>doclifter</command>
developers.</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry>
<term>-X</term>
<listitem><para>In batch mode exclude pages listed in the argument file.  
Meant to be used for pages that are known good and take an extremely
long time to lift, in order to cut down the time for a test run. (Most
pages lift in less than a half second, but a few can take 15 minutes
or longer.)
</para></listitem>
</varlistentry>
</variablelist>

<para><command>manlifter</command> emits a logfile to standard
output. The file begins with a timestamp line and a blank line,
and ends with a line giving run time and various interesting
statistics.  Between these are stanzas, separated by blank lines,
one for each file on which <command>doclifter</command> was
run.</para>

<para>The first line of each stanza beguns with "! ", followed by the 
pathname of the source manual pager, followed by "=" and the return
status of doclifter run on that file.  Following that is a space
and <command>doclifter</command>'s runtime in seconds.</para>

<para>This initial line may be followed by information messages and
the error output of the doclifter run.</para>

<para><command>manlifter</command> must find a copy of
<command>doclifter</command> in either the current directory or one of
the command directories in your <envar>PATH</envar> in order to
run.</para>
</refsect1>

<refsect1><title>Bugs</title> 
<para>HTML generation is painfully slow.  Unfortunately, there is
little we can do to remedy this, because XSLT engines are painfully
slow.</para>
</refsect1>

<refsect1><title>See Also</title>
<para>
<citerefentry><refentrytitle>doclifter</refentrytitle><manvolnum>1</manvolnum></citerefentry>,
<citerefentry><refentrytitle>xmlto</refentrytitle><manvolnum>1</manvolnum></citerefentry>
</para>
</refsect1>

<refsect1><title>Author</title>
<para>Eric S. Raymond <email>esr@thyrsus.com</email></para>

<para>There is a project web page at
<ulink url="http://www.catb.org/~esr/doclifter/">http://www.catb.org/~esr/doclifter/</ulink>.</para>
</refsect1>
</refentry>
